I agree
>> it is. Hello everybody. It is noon. So I
am going to call the
um January 20th public service committee
meeting to order. And once we are we
will go please um silence your phones or
put them on mute and once we are through
the agenda there will be no other
business to be heard. So with that
Jennifer would you please read in the
first item
>> number 10 ordinance third reading
creating chapter 1.28 2A administrative
inspection warrants establishing
authority for their issuance and
amending the municipal code of the city
of Cheyenne, Wyoming to authorize
certain city officials as specified to
apply for administrative inspection
warrants.
And do we have a staff report?
Councelor,
uh, Mr. Mr. Chairman, members of the
committee, John Brody, city attorney.
Um, this is on second reading. There was
obviously robust discussion and
consideration at the last council
meeting. I did prepare a substitute at
the request of Cheyenne Fire Rescue and
the chief building official, which I
believe you all have. Um, my office has
not received any comment, but I'm happy
to answer questions.
>> Questions from the committee.
Councilwoman?
>> Yes, sir.
Uh,
so many questions, so little time, Mr.
Brody. Um, but
I'm
I just want to make sure I have the
right substitute. I had received a
document from you on Friday afternoon
that on 128.020,
020 grounds for issuance. Um the word
probable was inserted in a in red and I
don't see it in this substitute.
>> Mr. Chairman, I'm not aware of the email
that I sent you. So I I'd have to look
at the email box. It may have come from
someone else, but
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you.
>> Any other questions for our attorney?
>> Mr. Chairman, if I may, just go ahead to
add on to that. I apologize. um you know
whether or not probable cause is in the
ordinance or not it doesn't matter.
Probable cause is the is the baseline
through which the warrant is issued. So
if it's in an administrative context
probable cause means you know clear
legislative standards periods of review.
If it's probable cause in the criminal
sense it's what would a reasonable
officer do you know under those
circumstances. So um oper from an
operative standpoint it it's not it
doesn't affect how the ordinance would
operate. how it would function.
>> Thank you. Any further questions?
Um, Councilwoman Aldridge, what's the
date on that email? I was trying to find
it.
>> I have to go back and look at my email.
I don't have access to my email from the
DIS.
>> Okay. And Mr. Chairman, I can look in my
email, but I I don't recall that email,
so maybe I'll get up here and beg your
forgiveness, but I'll look.
>> I thought I'd seen one recently that had
a an amend proposed amendment also.
That's why I was asking. So, okay. Thank
you. No, no further questions for our
attorney then. All right.
Um,
>> no, we need Yeah, I do need a motion and
then public comment. So, may I have a
motion?
>> Yes. Um,
>> point of order. We need public comment.
Uh, Mr.
>> We need a motion first.
>> Do before and then we make the motion.
Okay. I was going to go immediately to
public comment after the motion, but
we'll go back to routine.
So all right, public comment then on the
item. If any of you wish to speak, now's
the time to do so. Just come up to the
push the button on the microphone so the
green light comes on and please identify
yourself.
>> Mr. Chadwick, welcome.
>> Chadwick, president on council bluff and
also representing Shine Board of
Realators. Um, we still asked uh in our
email for a uh postponement and that's
what we'd like to ask for again just
because we just gotten the
documentation. We'd like to go through
and we'd like the ability to go through
and look at everything. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Good afternoon, council members. My name
is Patricia McCoy, and I am here to
express my gratitude for a shift in
direction. It has come to my attention
that Councilman White and Councilwoman
Aldrich have been working with legal
counsel and legislators to fix a heinous
error in the original draft of this
ordinance. By working to limit this
authority strictly and exclusively to
abandoned and unoccupied properties,
they are demonstrating what true public
service looks like. So, thank you for
listening to your constituents and for
respecting the sanctity of the Wyoming
home. However, as we move through this
committee process, we must ensure the
final language is bulletproof. To assist
in that effort, I've already emailed a
formal proposed amendment to each member
of this committee. This amendment is not
just about policy. It is about
constitutional survival. As I noted in
my email, the Wyoming Supreme Court has
made it clear in cases like OOIL versus
state and Vasquez versus state that our
state constitution article 1 section 4
is a higher shield than federal law. We
do not allow government fishing
expeditions in Wyoming. By limiting this
ordinance strictly to unoccupied and
abandoned structures, you solve the
city's safety concerns regarding trouble
spots without violating the rights of
law-abiding neighbors. It keeps the
government out of our living rooms and
maintains the council doctrine that
Wyoming citizens cherish. I urge this
committee to adopt the strict limitation
language I provided. Let's finish the
work Councilman White and Councilwoman
Aldrich have started and bring this
ordinance into compliance with our
state's proud legal tradition. We are
your neighbors and your employers and we
thank those of you who have chosen to
listen. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Miss McCoy.
>> Anybody else care to make a comment?
Yeah, my name is Ben Railen. I'm a
resident on Carmemell Drive and I was
>> What was your last name again?
>> Rail.
>> Okay.
>> And I was also going to be requesting a
postponement of this. I believe there is
an amicable way forward that uh certain
amendments could be reached that would
make this more tolerable to both parties
uh the public and the city council. And
I also am a board member of the board of
realtors and I've also been uh involved
with the new county regulation and
everything like that and the efforts
made there. Uh we were able to reach
something that was very amicable and
passable to everybody involved and I
think we could also do that same process
here and reach the same conclusion. We
just need a little more time. That's why
I'm asking for a postponement. Okay.
>> Thank you, Mr. Real.
Further public comment.
Public comment. Somebody online.
>> Mr. Jacobson, you should be able to
unmute yourself.
>> Good afternoon.
Um,
I didn't come in to ask for this, but I
do think a postponement delay of this
would be appropriate since there's
apparently been some changes that I'm
not aware of. I don't know where they
were published. If that's my fault, I
apologize. But I don't know where those
changes have been, where they've been,
and h how I missed them. I looked at the
ordinance that was forwarded to this
committee by the city council, and I've
reviewed that in detail, but there
apparently has been some changes. Can
anybody direct me to where that those
changes are and how I would access
those?
>> Well, at the moment there have not been
any changes, but um any adopted in any
any way, but Jennifer, can you answer
his question?
>> So, Mr. Chairman and committee members
and members of the public, I guess just
to be clear, there is nothing posted
online as far as changes or amendments
unless the committee or the full body
acts on them. So until there is any sort
of action on those amendments, they will
not be posted online for the public.
>> And I need you to identify yourself,
please.
>> Jennifer Mlen, executive city.
>> Oh, I was like, you need me.
>> The member of the public. Sorry.
>> Um, my name is Steve Jacobson.
>> Thank you, Steve. Any further comments
then after hearing that?
I do have more comments then.
>> Okay, go ahead.
>> Um,
uh, I think that, uh,
there's a
state statute 35-7-1046
which addresses all of this.
And I'm wondering why the city wants to
have something that is less
appropriate and consistent with the
state law. Uh this was brought up at the
city council meeting. I believe Mr.
Brody was not aware of this when he
wrote this wrote this uh ordinance.
And I would like to consider that as Mr.
Miller had brought pointed out to the
city council
that it has to be done with a district
court
judge and not a city municipal judge.
That's just one of the things that needs
to be done.
And I think that you're asking to create
something that is not necessary
because the section 35-7-1046
clearly states what can happen
or city folks can use this law to
administer what they need to have
happen.
So,
what is the reason to try to create a
another administrative law that is not
consistent with 35-7-1046?
>> Thank you, Mr. Jacobson.
>> Good afternoon, city council members.
Kathy Sigliano. Um, I would just like to
also express that I think a postponement
would be nice. Um, if things are going
to be amended today, I think that's
great. Um, but allowing the public some
time to review those amendments and then
possibly giving further public comment
at a later date would be amazing.
>> Hey, I would like to add that there will
be one more reading next Monday. So
public will have 5 days to look at any
changes made and comment at the council
meeting on Monday.
Pardon me.
>> Good afternoon, council. Um, I'm here to
speak on behalf of myself as a homeowner
as I have spoke as a realtor as well,
but today I'm going to speak as a
homeowner. your name, please.
>> Uh, Philip Bowling.
>> Thank you, Philip.
>> Philip with two L's. Bowling just like
the game.
>> Um, I wasn't at the last meeting, but I
did get to listen and watch it. And the
big things I did see that there is a
concern for this situation, and I do
think there are some good things that
have been done. One thing I think is
good is the situation with the fire
chief I think was really good because it
gave explanations, details, and also
ordinances that blankly show what the
reason is for. On the other side of
things, we didn't see that with other
things. I think unfortunately when it
comes to the wording that has been done
has left things very open to
interpretation of however we want it to
be instead of having the detail side
like we did with the fire side.
With those I also know in past
ordinances a big thing we say we want to
do is we want to make things happen
because we hear so many people that say
it. However, at the last meeting, I
heard that really in what, 11 years, um,
the city inspectors will had to use it
one time. So, now we're enforcing a law
that has to move forward for something
that doesn't happen a lot. The reason
why I bring that up, it brings me into
my next situation. I want to bring up
Liberty, whole different standpoint than
I've seen a lot of people do. Why I'd
like to um go ahead and quote Charlie
Kirk. So, Charlie Kirk used to say that
um, liberty inherently involves risk.
There are trade-offs to freedom. Kirk
argued that freedom and liberty come
with unavoidable consequences. For
example, in discussing the Second
Amendment, he said that having an armed
citizen near means gun deaths will
occur, just as we accept traffic deaths
because we choose to allow driving for
the benefits to it provides. He
described these outcomes as the price of
liberty and said that accepting some
risks is necessary to preserve
constitutional rights. So at the same
time from what I heard there wasn't a
substantial amount besides the um fire
department side of things that we need a
lot of it but other side I didn't hear
there was a ton of reasons there are
some stories which I've heard from you
guys are stories and the people have
stories as well too but at the end of
the day
the job for you guys is also to protect
us and our liberty as well and
unfortunately our liberty makes your
guys' life more difficult. It's not
meant for you guys to have a sensibility
to be easy. That makes our our life more
difficult. So, at the end of those
things, I have one last statement, then
I'll be done.
In Wyoming, liberty is not something
granted by government. It is something
government is meant to protect. Our
constitution reflects the truth by
placing limits on government power,
especially when it comes to private
property and the sanctuary of one's home
or business. Liberty is not always
efficient. It can be inconvenient. It
can frustrate enforcement. But those
inconveniences are not flaws in the
system. They are safeguards to keep the
power from growing unchecked.
This proposed ordinance lowers the
standard of government entry onto
private property. It allows
administrative warrants not only when
there is clear evidence of wrongdoing or
imminent danger, but also for routine
inspections or when officials believe
seeking consent might slow them down.
This is a meaningful shift when warrants
are no longer tied to specific
suspicion. They stop being a shield for
citizens and begin to function as a tool
of compliance.
I'm especially concerned because when
authority like this is created, it does
not expire on its own. It applies across
departments, across future councils, and
across circumstances we cannot foresee
today. Law should be written not just
for the best intentions of the present,
but the realities of the future.
Wyman has always believed the property m
property rights matter most when they
are inconvenient to the government, not
when they are easy. Consent that can be
bypassed when it comes when it becomes
frustrating is no longer meaningful
consent.
We should be very careful before
normalizing forced entry into private
property is a routine administrative
option. Public safety can be protected
without permanently expanding government
authority into places it has no
historically belonged.
I urge this body to either reject this
ordinance as it written substantially
written or substantially narrow it
because liberty because once liberty is
reduced it is rarely restored.
So as I said before I'm not saying we
have to completely remove it. I do
understand that we can maybe detail it
up. But I will tell you because I know
in the last thing there was comments
that everyone said there was fear. We
all have fear. I don't have fear. Be
honest with you. I'm not asking you to
go to my neighbor, double check their
house, walk through and say, "Hey, this
needs to be done. This needs to be
done." I'm not asking for that. So, I
don't have fear. Realistically, for me
as a homeowner, I don't want you to be
my parent. I don't want you to be your
own be everyone else's parent. Liberty
is responsibility of each and every
citizen out there. But liberty also
gives me the ability that I can be and
live my life. But also with that, there
are consequences. Some of those
consequences are maybe the house wasn't
up to code and does burn and burns mine
down. I'm willing to accept that ability
because I choose liberty over control.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Mr. Bowling.
Any further public comment in the room?
Anyone else online? Jennifer.
Okay. With no further public comment,
then may I have a motion?
>> Yes. Uh,
Chairman Renie, we have to remember
who's in the seat today.
Um, I would move to postpone for two
weeks.
>> You need a motion on the floor first.
>> I move to post. Oh,
>> we need a main We need a main motion
before we can postpone.
>> I I would move to adopt by substitution.
>> No.
>> Can I just move to adopt?
>> Yeah. Actually, and it's so to approve.
>> Yeah. Move to approve on third and final
reading. Is
>> there a second? Yeah, I'll second for um
postponement. and I move to postpone.
>> Second
>> discussion on the postponement.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Councilwoman,
>> um, Councilman Renie, I just there has
been a lot of discussion. We had a about
45 to 50 people show up on Saturday
morning for council and coffee. Um, a
lot of concern. We've had two attorneys
who have worked on this throughout the
weekend. Um we have several um points
that we believe are needed to be changed
in this. We also are working from two
different copies. Um and so in order to
prepare an I and a item that can
actually be passed by our body um that
is not um
for lack of a better term halfbaked. um
we really need to have some time to make
sure we're putting forth a quality
product that um our constituents and our
stakeholders and the council and um our
city staff can live with. So for that
reason um I would urge you to vote for
postponement.
>> Further discussion on the postponement.
Mr. Leborn, I saw you reaching for your
mic.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
I speak in favor of postponement
because of the confusion that is clearly
uh associated with this particular
action. It is something that um
I believe the council takes seriously,
the city staff takes seriously and
obviously the community takes very
seriously.
But there is a lot of real
misinformation here and misunderstanding
that I really really
don't know if those po postponement is
going to be able to put us into this
forum where we can reasonably discuss
this.
I don't think that
certainly in my case I'm not an
attorney. I don't want to argue the law.
I'm satisfied and anybody that wants to
uh and certainly I think we should
circulate it widely. The memo that our
city attorney prepared,
it is uh
not reasonable
to believe that we are interested in
going into someone's house
uh without probable cause and going into
someone's house. period. I I just want
to assure anyone who's listening and the
people that are here today
until you have dealt with some of these
problems,
it really seems
and and it truly is not a giant problem.
There probably aren't going to be a lot
of these,
but those cases do come up
and
there has to be a better understanding
of what happens with abandoned buildings
and
buildings that are partially burnt. It
happens and when it happens
there is a lot of um
law
that is property law. That means that we
cannot go into that situation,
identify all the problems,
bulldoze the building and acquire title
to that property. I mean, there have
been cases, I can think of one extreme
case where we had to do that. Um, and
particularly I would appeal to the
realtors that are here to consider what
an abandoned building does to a
neighborhood and a block
and the people that live there. They
really really
come to us and they want us to deal with
it and we want to deal with it.
It takes an inordinate amount of time
and
there are I'm I'm actually glad we're
having this discussion and I speak in
favor of the postponement.
It really is something that the
community needs to understand
understand better.
We don't want and the calls and the
email that I've gotten um
I read them. I responded to some of
them.
There is a fear factor here.
And let me say, you don't need to be
afraid of us.
No one needs to be afraid that we are
some kind of imports from somewhere
else. Um, I'm a native. I've been
dealing with this problem for many
years.
Um I'm
familiar with the reasoning behind this
proposed action
and
I am really concerned frankly
members of the committee and those that
are watching elsewhere
that we have to treat each other with
respect
and we have to talk to each other
and we have to talk about what is here,
not what is somewhere else,
not what the fear is. And I hope that
this postponement, as I believe it was
appropriate, will give us the chance to
do that and hopefully be able to really
get to the heart of the matter. And I
don't know if what all that includes.
Perhaps a tour of the abandoned
properties,
a explanation from our staff here, what
they do and how they do it, and an
understanding that our fire department
is not interested in we have the code.
We want to enforce the code. And so it
really is something that uh I hope we
can take advantage of what I believe
will probably be a postponement to work
this through so we don't have it again.
This cycle of belief that there's anyone
here in the city of Cheyenne that wants
to go into someone's house
without probable cause and good reason
without the authority being established.
and I believe the municipal court is the
proper venue and there'll be further
protections discussed here that uh have
been brought forward to us. So, um
I think that's all I've got to say right
now, but uh I
appreciate the concern that people have.
They want to postpone this and
understand it better. Good. It is not an
it's not an immediate emergency, but the
the whole purpose of this is in the
cases where you do have a an emergency
rarely,
but you got to deal with it. So, um I
hope we'll postpone it and hopefully
broadly discuss this and have an
opportunity for everyone to better
understand that we are not interested in
going into your house willy-nilly.
And we do have a problem and I can tell
you it is a very strange unbelievable
problem that people abandon property
that has a lot of value
but they do
and then we have to act on it. So um
thank you Mr. Moody. You haven't spoken
yet. Did you want to say anything?
>> I have two points of information please.
>> Councilwoman go ahead. Um I am wondering
if there are any of these if we have any
situations currently that are pending
that would need immediate attention by
for these um from our building code
enforcement or our fire department.
Can either member of the staff care to
answer that?
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Tonal Parmlo, building officials, city
of Cheyenne. Um, yes, sir. We do
currently have a property located at Hot
Springs and I believe it's 17th is the
corner. We've received numerous calls
from the homeowner that the house has
been taken over. It's been abandoned,
taken over by vagrants. I've conducted a
couple of site visits there. Been unable
to gain access to the property. Thus,
we've been unable to abort it and it's
it's open um uh to this day and um
unable to secure the property.
>> Thank you.
>> Question. Yeah. Thank you, Council
Rooney. A follow-up question. Um is a
twoe postponement going to be
problematic
um with that property. I mean to I
understand the urgency, but
I'm guessing that this has been going on
for quite a while.
>> Mr. Chair, through you to Dr. Alrich. Um
ma'am, the property has been in this
state for a couple of months now. Um I I
cannot speak to what tomorrow brings or
even this afternoon, honestly. Um, it is
a concern. It is especially a concern
for the people that live in the
neighborhood and the next door neighbors
that have children that are dealing with
what is uh currently taking place there.
That's the best I can answer it for you,
Dr. Aldrich.
>> Thank you.
>> My uh second point of uh information and
really clarification. Um there was some
confusion by uh committee members uh as
we were talking about this prior to the
meeting. Um that the way the current
current ordinance um proposed ordinance
is written um it is not and my
understanding is is not only abandoned
or unoccupied buildings um and nor was
the substitute only abandoned or
unoccupied buildings. But I want to make
sure that that's correct, that it
includes abandoned and unoccupied
buildings as well as those that may or
may not be occupied.
>> I think as well as suspected code
violations.
>> Mr. Chairman, John Brody, city attorney.
The the original proposal was, as you
indicated, it was not limited to just
abandoned structures. The uh substitute
um contains sort of three clarifications
when it comes to residential properties.
One of those clarifications is if the
owner or the owner's agent has requested
a permit through the chief building
official, then that would allow for uh I
guess enforcing the obligations tied to
the permit, but then abandoned
structures and fire code are the other
two.
So, as a followup, it could include um a
building that is actually currently
occupied
>> only in the context of if that person
has pulled a permit um under the
>> correct,
>> but a building official can probably
speak to that a little bit better.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you, Mr. Brody.
Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Three.
Uh thank you everybody for your uh
public comments. Um I do think it's
important you get this substitute uh out
there because we heard a lot of
postponements. So that's why I'll be
supporting post postponement. But thank
you again everybody for participating in
your government.
Okay. Further discussion on the
postponement.
Discussion on the motion to postpone
hearing. None. All those in favor
signify by saying I. I.
>> I. The recommendation to the council
will be to postpone for two weeks.
Next item, please.
>> Number 11, ordinance, second reading,
annexing to the city of Cheyenne,
Wyoming, various tracks of land
completely surrounded by current city
limits situate and eastern Cheyenne
generally generally located south of
Story Boulevard, east of Powder House
Road, north of Del Range Boulevard, and
west of Ridge Road.
staff report.
Chair and members of the committee,
Connor White Planning and Development
Department. Uh so the annexation before
you. This is for tracks of land that are
um north of Del Range and south of
Story, usually known as section 20. Um
and then there's a couple properties on
the east side of Converse.
Um
with the sanation, we did have the
public hearing last Monday. There was no
public comment. As I had mentioned, the
two major land owners in this area or
four these tracks of land are both in
favor of the annexation
um and support it. And then the other
two land owners, one being the city and
the other being the school district. I'm
sure the city doesn't mind because I
believe that track that we'd be annexing
is actually for a future fire station.
Um so that would be annexed into the
city and then the school district has
land out here. I'm not sure what for. Um
but they do own land in the area. Um
haven't had any comment from the school
district and again all the other
property owners. The other three are in
support. Um with that I stand for any
questions. Any questions for staff?
>> Okay. No questions. Thank you. Mr. White
normally would ask for a developer
report. This isn't really being
developed, but is there a representative
for the applicant that cares to address
this?
Okay.
Any public comment?
No public comment. May I have a motion?
>> I would move to approve on second
reading.
>> I'll second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Moody. Discussion on the
ordinance on second reading. Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman through
you. Um again as I said if landlords
asked be requested I'm going to honor
that request uh fulfilling a promise. Uh
thank you Mr. Chairman.
>> Further discussion
Mr. Leborn.
>> Thank you Mr. Chairman. Obviously this
is a
annexation that includes a lot of
property in an area that is under
surrounded by a lot of development.
And it is something that I think we can
look at and see
how our processes work and how uh this
property is going to be able to be
developed and the cows will have to find
another home. It is uh something that um
certainly has uh gone through many years
of discussion and planning. And so I
think it's only appropriate that we
annex it and begin to work on its
development because uh it is
uh probably the largest
piece of this uh type of property that
is going to come into the city and I
think it's only appropriate that we
annex it and reszone it. Thank you.
>> I think that the cows get to stay for a
while according to theou we approved
recently.
Darn it. I'd like to see those cows go
when the development proceed.
Thank you. Further comments.
All right.
So, we have a motion, a second. No
further discussion. All those in favor
of the ordinance on second reading
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> None opposed. Recommendation will be to
approve on second.
Number 12, ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, establishing the
zoning classifications of AG,
Agricultural, and MR medium density
residential for land annex to the city
of Cheyenne, generally located south of
Story Boulevard, east of Powderhouse
Road, north of Del Range Boulevard, and
west of Ridge Road.
>> Staff report, please. Chair, members of
committee, Conor Planning and
Development Department.
So, with any annexation, we always have
our assigned zoning. Um so with this
county pocket annexation the large
portion for section 20 staff would
recommend agriculture uh for that large
portion. Um reason being that there's no
proposal really for the development of
that entire section. Uh it's mostly
being used for agricultural at this
time. Agricultural zone is best for
holding zone. It's easier to reszone in
the future. Um there's several pro well
not several projects. There is a project
that we're aware of um on the west side
along Powder House that will be actually
platting and reszoning their portion
once the sanctation goes through um for
a development. So agriculture just makes
it easier to reszone as these
developments uh come in. Um that's also
another reason for the annexation
actually is it allows to just be under
one jurisdiction and not have to have
somebody they got to look at county
processes before they annex or whatnot.
So zoning at a allows just easier
redevelopment, easier reszoning. Uh the
parcels on the east side of Converse
staff would recommend those be medium
density residential. They're surrounded
by medium density residential over
there. Uh there is for the parcels that
are long converse there is some NR3 and
NR2 zoning which is higher residential
but staff doesn't feel that an assigned
zoning to a higher residential would be
best with an assigned zoning that should
go through a public process.
So that's why staff recommends just the
standard MR zoning. It does allow for
residential. Um, it would allow for
multif family if they went for
conditional use or they can go through
the public process, come back to council
and reszone it to a higher residential
if they so chose. Um, so again, the
larger portion of section 20 would be
agriculture and then the two on the east
side or the two pockets on the east side
of Converse, we would recommend medium
density residential. Planning commission
did hear this and did recommend approval
um of the assigned zoning. And I stand
for any questions.
>> Questions for Mr. White?
>> Yes, sir. Councilwoman,
>> uh, Councilman Ray through you. Um, I
was out on Powder House over the weekend
and noticed that we're noticing a um an
area between
Coyote Ridge School and Life Care, which
I believe is demonstrated on this map in
the brown area below the blue area.
Yeah. And I'm just wondering if
that notification
right now we're asking you're asking for
an agricultural zoning for that um
rather than going for the zoning that is
being proposed. I I believe it's for a
multi a multi- family senior housing
project for 60 60 and two and over or
something like that. No children
allowed. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Chair through you. um to
Councilwoman Aldrich. So, yes, they're
going to be coming before council uh to
request the NR3, which is neighborhood
residential high density uh for multif
family for uh senior housing. Um reason
staff wouldn't go with a recommendation
of um that as an assigned zoning, again,
it's the same thing with the parcels
that are on the east side of Converse.
Yes, there's NR3 in that area. There's
NR2 that was both of those NRS basically
that are up there were approved by
council for higher density. Those should
go through a more public process than
the city just saying we're assigning
that zone district. Um also
before we even had that proposal this
started through the process. We knew
that they were looking at proposing that
but with the way that currently the land
is that's what our assigned zoning takes
into consideration. Um, and that's why
we're just recommending zone of a DAG.
They're going to come back before you
with the NR3, which has comment letters
that go out to all the neighbors, the
whole public process for that zone
change. Um, and then it would be up to
council if you choose to approve that
NR3 for that specific lot.
Um, also with their zone change, it's
going to be tied to a plat that they're
also going to have come before council.
So, it's not we're not trying to assign
a zone to a larger area than what
they're trying to develop.
>> Any further questions for staff
hearing? None. There's Thank you, Mr.
White. There's not a representative for
the applicant. Is there any public
comment?
Public comment.
All right. May I have a motion?
>> Would move to approve on second reading.
>> Second.
>> Okay. Motion made by Alders, seconded by
Moody.
Discussion,
Mr. Leborn.
All right, cool.
>> Just waiting to move.
>> Okay.
All right. No discussion.
Discussion. Hearing none. All those in
favor signify by saying I. I. I.
>> The recommendation for Monday night will
be to approve on second.
Next item, Jennifer.
>> Number 13, ordinance second reading,
amending 5.7.3
accessory dwelling units of the Cheyenne
Unified Development Code. To remove
owner occupancy and adjust parking
requirements for accessory dwellings and
making conforming amendments to the
definitions of an accessory dwelling and
semi-attached dwelling under 1.4.4, 4
descriptions of uses of land and
buildings.
>> Mr. Lloyd, staff report, please.
>> Mr. Chair, members of the committee, my
name is Seth Lloyd. I'm with the City of
Shine Planning and Development
Department. The proposal in front of you
makes amendments to the Unified
Development Codes standards for
accessory dwelling units. Essentially,
it removes one requirement and changes
another one. The removal is for owner
occupancy and the change is to um the
parking requirements. Essentially, the
parking requirement change um
redefineses uh the extra space as being
anywhere um on the property as opposed
to being in a discrete portion of the
lot, allowing us to use um say a
threecar driveway or three um or on
street parking in the case of a corner
lot, whatever it needs to be to allow a
little more flexibility on the parking.
For the owner occupancy side of things,
um the current code requires owner
occupancy of an accessory dwelling unit.
So, if you have a single family home,
you can convert it to two units if you
are living in one of those two units.
Um, or you can add a garage on the back
with a dwelling unit above the garage.
Those are some options for an accessory
dwelling unit. Um, in under our current
unified development code, a flat over
flat duplex is considered a duplex. And
so, if you have enough street frontage
on your property, you can still do two
units even if you're going to rent out
both units and not live there. You just
have to have a certain minimum amount of
frontage. Um, in the unified development
code, for example, um, one of our lot
types requires a 30 feet of lot frontage
for a duplex. Um, so if you had a single
family home with 65 ft of lot frontage,
you could do two units as a flat over
flat duplex as opposed to as an
accessory dwelling unit. This does
trigger some changes in our building
code um, between the duplex and
accessory dwelling unit. um our building
official has in the past treated an
accessory dwelling unit as basically
extra rooms on a single family home
because the owner is living there.
Whereas if it's going to be two rental
units or a duplex or a flat or flat
duplex, it has to meet a higher standard
in the building code. Um so by changing
accessory dwelling units to being
allowed without um a uh owner being
occupied, the building code would look
at an accessory dwelling the exact same
way as they would look at a flat
overflat duplex. So, they would have
whether it's an accessory dwelling unit
or duplex, whatever you call it, it
would have to meet those fire and
building code standards. Um, in other
jurisdictions that have adopted uh ADUs
without owner occupancy requirements,
this is how the building officials all
look at them. It doesn't really matter
if it's a duplex or an accessory
dwelling unit, they always have to meet
building and fire code as if it was a
duplex. There's not really a it's more
of a zoning semantics than it is a a
building code semantics for those other
jurisdictions. Um so that would change a
little bit as far as construction of
materials go um for converting a house
to two units. Um as such um because the
differentiation between a flat or flat
duplex and ADU is basically lost. This
amendment also changes the definition
section of uh uses in the unified
development code to clarify that a flat
or flat duplex is always an accessory
dwelling unit. Um that also removes some
of the challenges staff had with using
the SD lot types in the unified
development code for duplexes because um
clearly when you look at the diagrams of
the SD lot types in the unified
development code, they consider
sidebyside duplexes. They don't really
consider the flat or flat version. And
so it was a little bit wonky to try and
apply um the standards of the SD lot
type to a flat overflat duplex. Um we
did our best we but by making this
change um that change would happen to
that section of code as well.
Um the uh I would note that there's been
um I mean obviously there's other
jurisdictions that have made this
amendment. The state of Montana as a
whole has made this amendment. Um and
there are various housing groups that
feel like this is a a good path forward
for addressing some housing concerns. Um
and as I noted previously, some lots can
do this anyway if they just have enough
frontage. They could rent out both units
if they just have enough frontage
because it becomes a flat or flat
duplex. So that is the impetus behind
this. Um I would also note that our uh
various agencies have written letters of
support which are attached in the packet
that you should have seen um supporting
this amendment. But I'm available for
any questions. Um oh I'm sorry. I also
should mention the planning commission
heard this item and also recommended
approval um with um very little changes
to the original uh document. Um I'm
available for any questions on this
item.
>> Questions for Mr. Lloyd? Yes,
Councilwoman Aldridge.
>> Uh, Councilman Renie, through you. Um,
I'm wondering I have two questions that
I'm wondering about. One is when we talk
about ADUs and we're talking about
renting out those items. Um, does this
also include the concept of Airbnbs? I'm
thinking of a individual I know that has
a house that has a basement apartment
where a property manager basically lives
and then rents out the main level for as
an Airbnb. So, this would include those
types of scenarios as well.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Um, generally
speaking, we have not developed any
specific regulations on short-term
rentals. So, from a zoning code
perspective, it has to meet the
standards for a dwelling unit. um which
a single family dwelling unit or in
order to meet the definition of dwelling
unit, you have to have a certain number
of um no more than a certain number of
unrelated people living there and you
have to have like a a dwelling like a
kitchen or something like that. So, um
it it gets a little hairy in terms of do
short-term rentals rent out bedrooms or
do they rent out entire units? Uh you
know, we we don't pay too much attention
to that unless there's a real strong
complaint about it. Um, but with
someone's renting out an entire unit,
they can rent out if they have an
approved ADU, they can rent out two
units. Um, whether that's for a year,
whether that's for a month, whether
that's for a day, whether that's for 5
years, whatever their contract is. Um,
they would be allowed to do that with
two approved units.
>> Okay. Um, and then as a follow-up, I'm
just wondering about um, I know when
Laramie looked at doing something very
similar, there was a huge concern around
uh, the university area with egress
windows and basements being rented out
to college students without egress
windows and the fire and the public
safety issues that were associated with
that. So, this would require those ADUs
if they were going to be utilizing or
had sleeping areas in a basement area to
meet the building code that requires
egress windows.
>> Mr. Chair, I'm not 100% certain as to
what our building officials would
require for a dwelling unit. Um, egress,
I believe, is a requirement. I don't
know what exactly what those uh
requirements are, but they would be
required to meet um building code
standards for egress for a a dwelling
unit. Um there might be something a
little bit different with existing
buildings, but I don't I can't really
speak to all those types of details. Um
presumably, um I know the standard for
new construction is to have egress
windows. Um so I would think that that
would be required, but I can't speak to
that with an existing building. They
might have some some flexibility built
into the building code. That would be a
question for a building official. And my
final question, uh, Councilman Renie for
you is, uh, with an ADU, they don't have
to have, um, cooking facilities,
correct? I mean, they can have a
kitchenet or something that's lesser
modified kitchen, but with a
uh actual unit, dwelling unit, um, my
understanding is that there actually is
a some sort of a kitchen aspect to that.
Mr. Chair, through you. Um, functionally
speaking, from a from a zoning code
perspective, um, it's really hard to
enforce someone's wet bar in a basement
or something like that. So, if someone
has a wet bar with a microwave and the a
sandwich maker or something, we're not
going to go in there and say, "Hey,
that's an ADU. You have someone else
living there." Um, pursuant to the
previous item on the agenda, we had a
long discussion about at council uh a
week ago. Um, we don't really go into
places and so our usual trigger point is
if you're starting to put in another
oven. Okay, you're putting in a second
oven in the basement, not on not, you
know, you're not a major cooker who's
just putting two ovens in the in your
main kitchen. So, usually that's our
trigger point. Um, if someone wants to
convert their single family home to a
semiadu situation and have kind of a a
wet bar situation in the basement,
that's not really something that we
enforce very well.
>> Okay. And sorry, one more followup. This
does not change our uh code, our
ordinance requirement right now that
there are no more than four adult
unrelated adults living in uh uh
property.
>> Mr. chair. The the way the regulation is
written is it's four unrelated adults
living in a dwelling unit. Um so under
the right circumstances, you could have
eight unrelated adults living in a
single family unit on the top and then
the second unit on the bottom. And
that's true of any duplex or a flat or
flat duplex approved in the city,
>> but they have separate entrances.
>> Uh Mr. Chair, I believe accessory
dwelling units have a separate entrance,
but that's another question for a
building official. I'm not clear on all
the details as far as um what
constitutes a dwelling unit, but I
believe that they would have separate
entrances.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman through
you. Uh thank you uh for all your hard
work on us, Mr. W. I know we had a long
discussion on this and that's why I'm a
sponsor. So, thank you so much.
>> Councilman Lebornne, any comments? No.
>> All right. Um any public comment?
Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman, members of
the committee. Dan Dors, executive
director for Habitat for Humanity of
Blairy County. One of those letters of
support that you should have received
was from myself. If not, I apologize,
but I'm just here to say I support this
amendment. Um, it's a good I believe
it's a good use to find creative ways to
add units in our community. Thank you
very much, and I stand for any
questions.
>> Any questions for Mr. Dorsch?
Okay. Thank you, Dan.
Further public comment.
Public comment. Nothing online,
Jennifer. Okay. All right. Then may I
have a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve on
second reading.
>> Is there a second?
Second. Motion made by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Leborn. Discussion
on
on the proposed ordinance?
>> Yes, sir. Councilwoman,
>> uh, Councilman Renie, uh, I'm going to
be a no vote today just because I have a
lot of unanswered questions that I would
like to have answered by our building
department, um, before I vote for this.
>> Thank you. Further discussion,
Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Uh, thanks, Chairman through. Um,
again, I do appreciate Lar's support. I
do think this is needed. Uh like we
heard the state of Montana is doing it
and actually the city and county of all
places Denver allows it too. So this is
cutting regulations that I've run on
that I ran on and making those promises.
So I look forward to going after more
UDC codes that can be eliminated make it
easier for more affordable housing. And
again I do appreciate the layers of
support for this. Thank you.
Further discussion
hearing? None. All those in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed.
>> No.
>> Okay. The recommendation will be to
approve on second.
>> Number 18. Resolution authorizing the
mayor and the city clerk to sign a final
plat for Cheyenne Business Parkway 15th
filing, city of Cheyenne, Laram County,
Wyoming. located east of Echoar Drive
and south of and adjacent to Camp Stool
Road.
>> Staff report, please.
>> Chair and members of committee, Conor
Planning and Development Department. The
final plat before you off camp stool. Uh
this is a subdivision of one lot into
six lots. One of the lots is proposed to
be a common lot um mostly for drainage
and things like that. Uh there is a
proposed street as well with the
subdivision uh to provide access to lots
and three I guess lot two as well of
block two. Um the whole property is
zoned hi heavy industrial. So this plat
is mostly for just creating additional
lots for heavy industrial or industrial
type uses or commercial uses out in this
area.
Um
the surrounding area is also hi um and
is industrial out here. So these lots
are pretty similar in size to what is in
the area.
Planning commission did hear uh this at
their meeting and did recommend approval
of this uh expedited plat. And I stand
for any questions.
>> Questions for Mr. White.
Thank you Mr. White.
Is there an report by a representative
for the applicant?
>> Good afternoon, chairman, members of the
committee. Casey Palma, Palma, land
planning agent for the owner. Uh, I
don't have anything to add. We do
currently have a um site plan approved
for development of lot one, block two.
Uh, and we will be um they'll be moving
forward with construction of that
roadway in the late spring, early summer
of this year. And I'd be happy to
address any questions you might have.
>> Any questions for Mr. Palmer?
>> Thank you, Casey.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Any other public comment
hearing? None. May I have a motion?
>> Move to adopt.
>> Second.
Okay, the motion is made by Councilwoman
Aldridge, seconded by Councilman Moody.
Discussion from the committee,
discussion
hearing. None. All those in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed. Recommendation will be to adopt
>> number 19 resolution certifying
compliance with Wyoming state statute
15-1-402
for the city annex the city initiated
annexation of various tracks of land
completely surrounded by current city
limit Situa in western and southern
Cheyenne generally located east of I25
south of the intersection of Westland
Road and Missile Drive north of west and
east Allison Road and east of and
adjacent to North College Drive.
>> Staff report, please. Mr. White, chair
and members of committee, Conor White,
Planning and Development Department. So,
this resolution, uh, this is basically
to initiate and start the final county
pocket annexation. Um,
so that's what this resolution is for.
With this annexation, um, staff did have
another, uh, public meeting, uh, with
the property owners. Um,
only one property owner showed up. That
property owner is also a property owner
not in favor. Um, but there was only the
one that showed up. I did get a phone
call from another property owner today
um, in parcel
7, which is off of College Drive. It's
one of the commercial lots over there.
Um, they just had questions more to
provide to corporate, but didn't seem as
if they were opposed to it. Um they
actually he told me that this by doing
this annationation it might give them
more flexibility and ability to um at a
later date provide some fire suppression
in their building if needed. Um
so they're don't they don't seem uh to
really mind the annexation. They're
going to let corporate know. The only
property owner that showed up was parcel
4. Uh, which is believe it's WY farms or
WFresh Farms over on Walterside. Um,
they're not really in favor of the
annexation. They were the only property
owner that did show up. Haven't heard
from actually I did hear from one other
property owner. Sorry, trying to think
back to all the weeks prior uh with how
long I have to set up moving this
forward. Uh, one other property owner
did call. She mostly just had questions
as what was going to be required. uh
within city limits if she wanted to add
a house to the other lot that she owns
that is in
parcel five. Um she owns basically a
parcel in there that is technically two
lots um by legal description and was
just wondering what it would take to add
another residential unit. What the city
requirements are um otherwise she was
perfectly fine uh with the annexation.
Again, this is just the resolution to
kick off the annexation. The proposed
schedule for this annexation would be a
public hearing on February 9th. Uh the
assigned zoning goes to planning
commission on February 2nd and then this
would all finish up on March 9th.
So that would be the estimated timeline
for this um with that resolution
and letters have been sent to all the
property owners already for the
annexation letting them know of all
those dates.
Um,
again, this is just a resolution to move
or to initiate the annexation itself.
With that, I do stand for any questions.
>> Questions for Mr. White. Councilwoman
Aldrich.
>> Councilman Renie uh through you. Did the
individual who showed up at the meeting
um from this WildFresh Farms um express
what their concern was about being
annexed? Was it just the activities
currently taking place there?
>> Mr. I chair through you. Um
really a lot of their complaints were
they don't believe the city is a good
neighbor.
Um
they don't want to be in the city. They
don't want to follow city regulations.
The typical we've heard with any of the
annexations.
I did explain to them um and actually
Chief Dyron was there with me. Um, it
was just me and uh, chief with this
meeting and
I explained to them that we're not
changing how they use the property. Most
likely staff's going to recommend that
council even zone it agriculture so they
can continue their agricultural use,
which wouldn't then change anything
they're doing. Uh, explain they don't
have to hook to city water and sewer.
Explain they can still use the property
the exact same way they're using it. So
most of their complaints were just I
think a lot of things that wouldn't
change even if they weren't annexed. Um
is kind of the impression that I was
getting because a lot of the complaints
seem like they're dating back to things
they have complaints about the city from
10 years ago, 15 years ago.
So
even with the annexation,
even if we didn't annex them, none of
their complaints are going to change. um
is the feeling that I was getting from
just talking with them. Um
but yeah, I would say it was the usual
complaints that we've gotten with any of
the county pocket annexations. Um I just
don't believe that a lot of their
complaints would change regardless of
what we did. Um they would still have
the same complaints and the same
dislikes with the city.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other questions for Mr. White? Is
this Mr. White? Is this parcel you said
was on Walter side is it the the
northern partial parcel the larger of
the two?
>> Uh Mr. Chair. Yes. So on the small map
which can't really see it on the screen
but um I know in the packet it's not the
exact annexation maps in the packet.
It's ones that I had to put together
because I didn't have the annexation
maps at the time of the resolution. I
can actually I can go to this one. Um
but yes, it's that northern large um
>> it's about
eight acre almost nine acres of land um
that they own, but it's the northern one
on Walter Shide that would be
>> okay
>> that parcel. Otherwise, as I mentioned,
that was the only property owner that
I've had contact me out of the 16
parcels um that isn't in favor. The city
does own land as well in uh this
annexation. It's actually a very small
strip up in parcel one that gets kind of
used as an alleyway.
Um but it is a parcel that the city owns
>> and then there's two right ofways for
Burlington Northern that are in this as
well.
>> Um that's right.
>> But yes, otherwise no other contact.
I've had just the three property owners,
two that aren't necessarily against it
and then just the one that I know is not
really in favor.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Um
any other any public comment then?
Public comment.
Hearing none, I need a motion to adopt.
>> I move to adopt. Is there a second?
All right. Hearing no. None. The motion
dies. For lack of a second, there will
be no recommendation.
>> Number 21A. Preliminary plat for Dry
Creek Vista
Vista. I don't know why. City of Lurmy
County, Wyoming, located northeast of
the intersection of Frank Court and Rock
Springs Street.
>> Mr. Roy, do you have this one also?
>> Chair, members of committee, counterway
planning and development department.
Yes, I do have this one as well.
Um, so the plat before you, it's
actually it's a preliminary plat. So
this is not a final plat. Uh, this
doesn't have a resolution. Uh, there
wouldn't be any myars that would be
signed or anything like that. Um,
so I'll do just a little bit of quick
kind of explanation because we don't
have many preliminary plats that come
before council. They're usually
expedited. So you're seeing the final
plat, you're usually approving those and
then they basically get myar signed and
the land is now platted with the
preliminary plat. Um basically with this
um it was submitted expedited as
expedited, but as staff was reviewing
it, staff had a lot of concerns about
that moving forward as expedited. A lot
of the concerns had to do with um the
proposed vacation of Frank Court,
ownership issues in the area. Um
there wasn't really many concerns about
what they were trying to do in creating
the individual lots. It was more or less
the issue with ownership and the
vacation of Frank Court. Um
in this area there's an east west right
of way uh that at the time of the
Smittle staff wasn't sure if that was
ever properly vacated. Um, my
understanding is county commissioners
finally because of this had a resolution
maybe like a week or two ago that went
back before them to to officially vacate
and record that document to make sure
that it was actually vacated. Um, and
then with this as well, the applicant
was looking at only vacating half of
that north section of Frank Court.
through staff's review, staff would
actually prefer to see all of that
section of Frank Court be vacated. Um,
and the reason for that is this really
is just being used as a driveway for
that northern lot.
So, with reviewing this plat and all the
various concerns, that's why it ended up
coming preliminary
um rather than expedited in having a
final plat. But what this preliminary
plat does um does allow basically the
applicant to move forward still um
getting all the clarifications and
everything come back before you with a
final plat um and that's why there also
some conditions within the approval of
this preliminary plat.
Um some of those conditions being that
the applicant provide um vacation map to
the city and the city will actually
initiate the vacation. The reason the
applicant can't do the vacation is
because they're having difficulty
getting the neighbors to sign off on the
vacation. So, if the applicant provides
um
uh basically they want to vacate the
street, you have to get all neighbors to
vacate that street because half the
street goes back to that neighbor.
Um but the city can actually initiate a
vacation and just vacate a street
without signatures.
So
with one of the conditions, we would
actually have the applicant provide the
city the map and then we would initiate
that vacation to vacate the street and
then they would final plat uh the
portions that um would go back to their
properties and provide the necessary
easements.
And then also uh one of the conditions
is to clarify and verify the owner and
dedication information
and then again provide necessary
easements and technical corrections with
the plat.
So those are the conditions that staff
uh recommends with the preliminary plat.
These are approved by planning
commission and then they come to city
council for basically um concurrence of
that approval.
Planning Commission did re or did
approve the preliminary plat um at their
meeting and I do stand for any
questions.
>> Mr. White, in going through the staff
recommendations and conditions, you
didn't address 1A. Is that not
recommended?
>> So, Mr. Chair, through you. Um sorry.
So, that is for the block size
exemption. Um,
basically there isn't really room in
here to add additional streets and the
block size is larger than we would
usually allow for block sizes. We have
seen this exemption.
>> So that's that recommendations taken
care of with the approval of the plaid
anyway.
>> Correct.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Any other questions for staff?
Any questions?
>> I have one more Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Uh, thank
you, sir. Um, did the neighbors go to
the uh planning commission to express
their disapproval at all or have they
contacted you?
>> Mr. Chairman, uh, through you.
>> No, there has not. Um, neighbors haven't
commented. I'm not sure why the
neighbors won't sign off on wanting to
vacate the street. Why or why not? Uh,
maybe the applicant can answer that or
if they just haven't even felt like
answering the applicant back. Um, I'm
sure the applicants probably tried to
reach out to basically say, "Hey, we
want to basically vacate the street. It
doesn't really benefit anybody. Nobody's
really using it, even the neighbors to
the west. Uh, one is a larger multif
family development. They're not using it
as access. Uh, it's basically the back
edge of their property. And then the
corner lot on the south, I think they
kind of use it, but maybe not as a
driveway as well." Um, actually part of
their I think part of their um patio
could even possibly be within it. Um, so
there's a bunch of things there that I
don't know if I can answer why or why
not they haven't answered. They didn't
come to planning commission. Um, they
would have received or actually I guess
with plats we don't provide there would
have been a sign out there at least that
shows that a platting action is going
on. Um, but maybe the applicant can
provide information if if or why they
haven't responded or if they don't want
to be a part of the plat itself. Um, but
that's why
if the vacation is going to move
forward, the city would have to initiate
that vacation.
Councilman Moody, anything else?
>> Uh, that's it. Thank you, Councilwoman
Aldrich.
>> Um, Councilman Renie throughu. I'm
assuming that the applicant is not here
today.
>> Mr. Thu, yes.
>> Nope.
That's
>> so that'll be the next person to come up
and speak.
>> Thank you.
>> If there are no more questions for
staff, is there a representative for the
applicant here?
>> Good afternoon, chairman, members of the
committee. Casey Palma, Palma land
planning agent for the owner. Um, I
think staff covered it pretty well. Um,
I would note that we, you know, on the
face of it, this is actually relatively
simple application. There's two
residences on the property. One of them
is currently served by water and sewer.
Um
there is a very convoluted and somewhat
vague and conflicting records regarding
this property, the adjacent rights of
way, what's transpired over time. In
fact, that north section of Frank Court
uh has been renamed three times uh over
the years. And uh the east west section
that staff mentioned um was vacated in
1989 by the county commissioners but uh
not recorded in a form that the current
assessor recognizes. Um so from a survey
perspective it's absolutely vacated but
from the assessor's perspective it may
or may not have been. So, as staff
noted, commissioners voted back on the
8th of January uh new new prompt to sort
of retroactively um acknowledge the
previous vacation and and formalize
that. Um so, some of these issues
regarding the title and the different
different pieces have been mostly worked
out at this point. Um, but when we
turned the the application in and
through the review process, some of
these things came up that uh there were
just questions about or you know, let's
let's do a little more digging to make
sure we get it right. So that's why we
were amendable to separating the
preliminary plat out and just just
hearing it separately, having you all
and the council acknowledge receipt of
that um as all of these things were
worked out. Uh in the meantime, I would
note that um we are okay with the staff
conditions as written. they were kind of
expected and and we're uh totally fine
with that. Uh regarding the neighbors,
there's two neighbors adjacent to this
plat to the west or adjacent to Frank
Court to the west. The apartments um we
have talked with their registered agent
a couple times. Um they have no sort of
no feelings one way or the other. They
said great, if you vacate it, that makes
our backyards bigger. Um that's about
their only concern with it. Um,
obviously neither of these rights of way
are going to extend across Dry Creek
Parkway at any point. So, the intent of
my client is just to kind of clean this
up, get rid of these public rights, the
way that they've been maintaining for
years. Um, and and just sort of sort of
clean everything up and and set it right
for the record. So, that's that's the
the only intent of this application at
this time. There's no development
proposed. Um the other neighbor there
next to Frank Court is we've just had
trouble getting a hold of them. So we
we've tried several different methods
and um finally
gave up on it to some extent because we
we couldn't get a hold of them and um as
you can see on the preliminary plat we
we proposed not to vacate that chunk of
Frank Court. Um one that avoids them you
know having a conflict with that. Uh, as
staff noted, I think they do have some
improvements out in the right ofway. Um,
so, you know, they could they could
address that separately rather than us
getting in the middle of that
conversation. Um, also, BOPU has
facilities in that chunk of rightway
that we're proposing to leave on this
map. Um, and so that also presents
complications. If we vacate that, then
the board wants uh an easement there.
uh our talks with the engineering
department at BOPU is that we don't
really think those are going to go
anywhere. They they were kind of
provided at a time when we thought that
street might go through. And so, um as
staff noted, I don't think there's any
major issues with the plat itself or
what's being done here. There's just a
lot of those kind of weird little nuance
pieces that um we've been putting
together. In the meantime, we'll
continue to do so, working with staff to
provide that um city initiated vacation
and uh you should see a a final plaque
coming forward and all of the issues
that that had come up will be resolved.
So, with that, I'd be happy to address
any questions you might have.
>> Questions for Mr. Palma?
>> Thank you, Casey.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Any public any other public
comment?
Public comment. Hearing none, then I
need a motion to approve.
>> I would move to approve with staff
recommendations.
>> Two staff recommendations to three.
>> Second for discussion.
>> Okay. All right. So, Councilwoman
Aldridge and Council Moody, including
staff recommendations numbers two and
three.
Discussion.
Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Uh, thank you, Mr. Chair. Three.
Uh, thanks for the information. Um, for
now I'm going to be in no vote because I
do want to if the neighbors can attend
just hear their perspective on it. Want
to respect their rights as well. Um,
just want to hear from them. Thank you,
Mr. Chairman.
Further discussion
hearing? None. All those in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Any opposed?
>> No.
>> Mr. Moody is a no vote. The
recommendation will be to approve the
preliminary plat. That concludes our
business. We are adjourned.